

# Pablo Martínez Agulló

PhD in Physics
Expert on data analysis using deeplearning algorithms

After completing my PhD in Particle Physics, I am looking forward to new challenges. I conducted my research with the ATLAS collaboration at the European Organisation for Nuclear Research (CERN), where I analysed data from the Large Hadron Collider (LHC). While working at the Instituto de Física Corpuscular (IFIC), I developed several frameworks for deep learning to boost our research. My main interests are artificial intelligence and the R&D projects.

### EDUCATION

#### 2017-2024

PhD in Physics | University of Valencia (Spain)

#### 2016-2017

MSc in Advanced Physics | University of Valencia (Spain)

#### 2015-2016

Erasmus | RTWH Aachen University (Germany)

#### 2011-2015

Degree in Physics | University of Valencia (Spain)

# EXPERIENCE

September 2019 – March 2024



IFIC/CERN | Researcher (Spain/Switzerland)

- Analysis of large volumes of data
- Use of advanced statistical techniques for data interpretation
- Development, optimisation, and integration of supervised Deep Learning models
- Translation of scientific theories into algorithms
- Collaborative software development
- Use of version control systems
- Presentation of results at national and international conferences
- Data taking responsable for the ATLAS detector

February 2020 – September 2021



University of Valencia | Lecturer (Spain)
• Teaching and assessment of the courses

Electromagnetism and Physics Laboratories

April 2019 – August 2019



Capgemini | Data scientist (Spain)

- Consultant in the Insights & Data team
- Development of a sentiment analysis tool based on web scraping and Natural Language Processing (NLP)

December 2017 – January 2019





IFIC/CERN | Researcher (Spain/Switzerland)

- Data analysis in the ATLAS collaboration
- Development of front-end and back-end web service to monitor the performance of the ATLAS detector
- Development and integration of tools for detector simulations

June 2016 – September 2016



ESA | Internship (Netherlands)

- Internship at the European Space Agency (ESA) and Leiden University
- Study of the impact of outreach multimedia using an NLP-based application

# RESEARCH STAYS

May - July 2022



CERN (Geneva, Switzerland)

September – December 2018 CERN (Geneva, Switzerland)



March - May 2018

CERN (Geneva, Switzerland)



# OUTREACH

- Contributor to the physics podcast Oscilador Armónico (2023 - 2024)
- Speaker/host of the public event 10° aniversario del descubrimiento del bosón de Higgs (700+ attendees, 2022)
- High school talks: ¿De qué está compuesta la realidad? (2022-2023)
- Video *LHCRun3* (20k+ views, 2022)
- Organizer of the science fairs *Expociencia* and *Experimenta* (2019-2022)

### HARD SKILLS

- Programming:
  - Languages: Python, Bash, C++, SQL,
  - Code optimisation skills
  - GitHub/GitLab, CI/CD, Docker
- Data science and Deep Learning libraries:
  - Pandas, NumPy, SciPy
  - PyTorch, XGBoost, keras
  - ROOT TMVA
  - BeautifulSoup
- Studies in Artificial Intelligence and Deep Learning
- Experience in AI projects: BDT, NN, NLP, etc
- OS: Linux, MacOS and Windows
- Conversion of scientific theories into algorithms
- Statistics and mathematics
- Cloud computing
- Learning/improving: TensorFlow, NLP

#### CONTACT



pablo.martinez.agullo@gmail.com



+34 616747286



LinkedIn: pablo-martinez-agullo



scholar: Pablo Martínez-Agulló



orcid: 0000-0001-8925-9518



iNspire: @1788391



GitLab: @martinpa



GitHub: @MartinezAgullo

# SCOLARSHIPS

- 2019: Scholarship from the Valencian Government (GVA) for the hiring of research personnel
- 2017: Severo Ochoa Collaboration Scholarships at CSIC Centers of Excellence at IFIC

### SOFT SKILLS

- Teamwork
- Autonomy
- Leadership
- Very good communication and interpersonal skills
- Creative problem-solving
- Large experience in international environments
- Enthusiasm for learning
- Time and deadline management
- Critical thinking

### LANGUAJES

• Spanish :: Native

English :: Professional

Catalan :: NativeGerman :: Basic